photonengine.com 2019-04-26

# Multiplayer Game Development Made Easy | Photon Engine

This is the privacy and cookie policy for the Exit Games Websites. Exit Games consists of: Exit Games Inc. (USA), Exit Games GmbH (Germany).

Personal data you voluntarily provide us through this site (which may include your name, company, address and contact details such as your telephone number, email address or fax number) will be used for the purposes of satisfying your requests, such as ensuring an error-free and comfortable usage of our websites and registration with Photonengine.com services.

If you have emailed us with an enquiry we will use your email address to respond to your query.

If you registered as a developer with Photonengine.com, we may collect personal data in order to administer your membership, including your log-in and password details in connection with your membership sign-in. We may also send you further information about our services or through our periodic newsletters, which may be unsubscribed by you at any time with a link that is provided with the newsletter.

You can tell us not to contact you with updates and information regarding our products and services at any time by contacting us using the contact details at the end of this privacy policy.

The above-mentioned data will be processed on the legal basis of Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation). Our legitimate interest follows the data collection purposes listed above. In regard to registered developers, the legal basis of the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. b GDPR, as far as the personal data is necessary for the performance of our contract with you as a registered developer.

The provision of personal data for registered developers is a contractual requirement, as we may not be able to provide you with our services without it.

Our website, the Photonengine Dashboard and Forum are using cookies. Detailed information about cookies can be found below.

We do not use automated decision-making, including profiling. 

##  With whom is the collected information shared? 

We may disclose your personal information to our offices or to our agents or contractors (hosting providers,cloud service providers, marketing service providers) who assist us in providing the services we offer, such for example in fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analyzing data, providing support services or in other tasks from time to time. Our agents and contractors will only use your information to the extent necessary to perform their functions.

In the event that we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, we may transfer any personal data we hold about to that re-organised entity or third party.

We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law, Court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of Exit Games, the Exit Games website or its visitors. 

##  International transfers 

Exit Games uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run Exit Games’ Websites and services.

Information that you submit may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By way of example, this may happen if one or more of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside the EEA or one of our service providers is located in a country outside the EEA. If you make contact with any business featured on the site your details may be transferred outside the EEA. If we transfer your information outside the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

We transfer personal data to the following third countries:

Third country | Legal safeguards  
---|---  
Australia | Standard Contractual Clauses  
Brazil | Standard Contractual Clauses  
Canada | Standard Contractual Clauses  
China | Standard Contractual Clauses  
India | Standard Contractual Clauses  
Japan | Standard Contractual Clauses  
Netherlands | Standard Contractual Clauses  
Russia | Standard Contractual Clauses  
South Korea | Standard Contractual Clauses  
USA | US-EU Privacy Shield / Standard Contractual Clauses  
  
To get a copy of the respective safeguards, please contact us at  
Exit Games GmbH, Hongkongstraße 7, 22457 Hamburg, Germany 

##  Use of cookies by Exit Games 

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently to improve the user experience, as well as to provide certain information to the owners of the site. Exit Games’ website sets cookies which remain on your computer for differing times. Some expire at the end of each session and some remain for longer so that when you return to our website, you will have a better user experience.

Detailed below are the cookies we use and why and how long they last.

**Google Analytics (used on all pages)**

Cookie | Description | Expires after  
---|---|---  
_gid | Used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
_gat | Used to distinguish users. | 1 minute  
_ga | Used to throttle request rate. | 2 years  
  
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form (using the option “anonymizeIP”), including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

**Homepage (https://www.photonengine.com/)**

Description | Expires after | Cookie  
---|---|---  
UserArea | Storing the current website area/ product page | 14 days  
  
This cookie is used to provide an easy navigation service in Photonengine Dashboard.

**Dashboard (https://dashboard.photonengine.com/)**

Description | Expires after | Cookie  
---|---|---  
UserArea | Storing the current website area/ product page | 14 days  
egfaL | Used to distinguish users. | End of session  
egcaL | Used to distinguish users. | 1 week  
  
These cookies are used to identify the logged-in user and provide data from the Photonengine services.

**Documentation (https://doc.photonengine.com/)**

Description | Expires after | Cookie  
---|---|---  
ASP-Net_SessionId | Used to distinguish users. | End of session  
  
This is a cookie that ASP.NET uses to store a unique identifier for your session. The session cookie is not persisted on your hard disk.

**Forum (https://forum.photonengine.com/)**

Description | Expires after | Cookie  
---|---|---  
cf_duid | Used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
vf_photon_TNH4Q-Vv | Used to distinguish users. | 20 minutes  
vf_photon_TNH4Q-tk | Used to distinguish users. | End of session  
vf_photon_TNH4Q | Used to distinguish users. | 1 month  
  
These cookies are used to identify the user within the Exit Games „Vanilla Forum“ and also provide internal analytics about the forum usage. This data helps us to identify important topics and to improve Photon services.

**Blog (https://blog.photonengine.com/)**  
No additional cookies are used on our Blog Website. 

##  The use by Exit Games of Google Analytics Cookies 

We collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns by using Google Analytics cookies. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information does not identify visitors or collect any personal details. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our websites. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personal information from any source. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to use it for. 

###  Google Analytics browser Opt-out 

To provide website visitors with more choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics, Google have developed the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. The add-on communicates with the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js) to indicate that information about the website visit should not be sent to Google Analytics. The Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on does not prevent information from being sent to the website itself or to other web analytics services.

##  Control of Cookies 

Web browsers allow you to exercise some control of cookies through the browser settings. Most browsers enable you to block cookies or to block cookies from particular sites. Browsers can also help you to delete cookies when you close your browser. You should note however, that this may mean that any opt-outs or preferences you set on the site will be lost. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit allaboutcookies.org which includes information on how to manage your settings for the major browser providers 

##  Retention Periods 

We will retain personal data only for as long as it is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed. 

##  Your Rights 

**You may object at any time to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes.**

If the processing is based on consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

You have the following rights:

  * The right to require free of charge (i) information whether your personal data is retained and (ii) access to and/or (iii) duplicates of personal data retained; 
  * The right to request proper rectification, removal or restriction of your personal data; 
  * Where processing of your personal data is based on legitimate interests according to Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR, the right to object on grounds relating to your particular situation at any time. If you object we will no longer process your personal data, unless there are compelling and prevailing legitimate grounds for the processing or the data is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; 
  * Where processing of your personal data is either based on your consent or necessary for the performance of a contract with you and processing is carried out by automated means, the right to receive the personal data concerning you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or to have your personal data transmitted directly to another company, where technically feasible (data portability); 
  * Where processing of your personal data is based on your consent, the right to withdraw your consent at any time without impact to data processing activities that have taken place before such withdrawal or to any other existing legal justification of the processing activity in question; and 
  * The right not to be subject to any automatic individual decisions which produces legal effects on you or similarly significantly affects you. 

To exercise the rights referred to above, please contact us privacy@photonengine.com. You have the right to take legal actions in relation to any breach of your rights regarding the processing of personal data, as well as to lodge complaints before the competent data protection authorities.

Please email any questions, concerns or comments you have about this policy to:

Exit Games Inc.  
121 SW Salmon ST STE 1100  
Portland, Oregon 97204  
USA  
privacy@photonengine.com

You may contact our Data Protection Officer at [privacy@photonengine.com](mailto:privacy@photonengine.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).
